# MATTHEW TAYLOR

Dependable and charismatic teacher with eight years of experience teaching 3-5-year-olds in a classroom setting. Passionate about the importance of early childhood education with a recognized ability to develop the students' skills and confidence through creative learning.

123 Main Street, Orlando, FL12345 matt.taylor@youremail.com (012) 345-6789

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# PRESCHOOL TEACHER

Kids Place Preschool, Orlando, FL September 2015 - Present

- Del i ver fun, i n te ra cti ve a nd c reative lesson s to a grou p of 4-5-yea r-o l d s with a n
  average of 16 students per class.
- Develop and coordinate fun and age-appropriate field trips for students each term.
- ♦ Establish basic literacy and maths skills in students
- Develop strong and lasting relationships with parents and children
- ♦ Foster a warm and welcoming atmosphere in the classroom

# PRESCHOOL TEACHER

The Jupiter School, Orlando, FL September 2012 - July 2015

- Praised by the school administration for automating the school student
   record-keeping process, which resulted in a 20% increase in information accuracy
- Delivered creative and unique lessons to groups of students aged from 3-4 years old with an average class size of 10 students
- Implemented multiple music and art-related activities that improved the students' creative skills
- Fostered a warm and caring atmosphere in the classroom to ensure the children
  felt safe and loved at school

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Arts in Early Childhood Education

University of Orlando, Orlando, FL September 2006- June2010

Master of Arts in Early Childhood Education

University of Orlando, Orlando, FL September 2010 - June 2012

#### **KEY SKILLS**

- Problem Solving
- Excellent Communication
- ♦ Loves Children
- ♦ Friendly
- ♦ Passionate About Education
- ♦ Childhood Development
- ♦ Creative Lesson Planning
- ♦ Adaptable to New Situations
- ♦ Excellent Leader

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

♦ Certified Infant and Child CPR